How to implement the breadth first search algorithm in see?
We will start by creating that queue structure queue.
It contains a array and items of size that we have created as 40, we defined it as 40.
We have an in front and rear.
OK.
These are for the queue.
If we have their size, we have.
There are a.
And items have the front, and we have that it.
OK, now we create the note.
This is the structure of the graph containing an end to vertex and struck note next.
OK.
This is the pointer and this is the vertex of the.
And this is their vertex and containing the data of it.
We create a graph here.
Extract node or struct graph and number of vertices, how many vertices that were going to create in
this graph and struct node, we create adjacent list and invest.
OK.
Now, the beef as the algorithm starts by telling us that.
We create a new method is this beefsteak in the perimeter of the graph and and start vertex as 30 meters.
We create the cue cue from the structure cue and this object or this pointer, we will use it later
on.
We start by graph to visit the visited array of the graph at Index Start Index equal to one.
And in queue, we are going to add.
Q, the two Q, we at the start first.
OK.
So for that, Q Q, we add the start index.
We start by making the while loop is checking if the Q is not empty.
We print the Q.
We initialize and add in variable called current Vertex, and we use the deck method here.
We have used their cue algorithm that queue data structure in order to help their breadth first search
algorithm to be implemented correctly and see.
Now, in the same way where I am going to use that while stamp is equal to true.
Now we make adjacent first text that at the vertex of the temp and we start by the visit that graph
and we ink you, we add them to that JSON vertex.
And later on, we move them to next.
Now let's create the node.
This method that we have seen at the very common in the previous videos create the node.
We initialize the node Malaak.
By creating either serving the memory, we created the Vertex V.
We get the data on it equal to V.
We initialize it and assign it to the past 30 meters fee and we point then next to equal to none.
OK, no.
We create a graph here.
In the same way as in the previous videos that we have used and how to do is to create the craft, so
I'm not going to go deeply inside it, just thinking and reserving the memory for the graph.
And we add the number, according to number of vertices is called Create the vertices as Andrea signed
them by using it for glue and we start adding them to adjacent list and the visit that list.
OK.
Also, that edge method add edge.
We have added them in the previous videos, so this will take in the perimeter of the graph that we
are going to to add to edges inside that the insource the vertex like this one and two, these are the
vertices is I am going to link them, so I will add edge between them.
I will add from one to two, so one will be passed as source and destination is two.
OK.
So the first one is the source and the second one is the destination.
We start by linking them here and the at the edge from the destination to source like this.
OK, now let's create the queue, create the queue by creating a new construct code struct node you
pointer and queue.
If Malak, we are reserving the memory and we initialize, it's four different if we're minus one and
three equal minus one.
Now we will continue by creating this is the queue, the structure of that queue, you can ask.
You can check it in the queue data structure lessons and learn more about the queue in the previous
pages and the previous sections.
OK.
No, I will create the queue here by using the Queue Create queue.
I will check it if it is empty.
I will end queue.
So in queue will add items to the to the queue and removing items from that queue.
OK.
So I want from you to go back to the queue section and learn more about these methods because they are
very important and they we have used them inside that before us.
OK.
Now printing the cure, it's very simple, going through all the elements of the queue while checking
if there's not empty by making a for loop, starting from the front and reaching the rear plus one.
For testing, I will create the main.
Create an instance of a pointer of a graph.
I will add the graph zero one zero two.
These are edges.
See, we are connecting zero to one zero two two one two two one two four one two three two, two four
and three to four.
OK, and I call this method BFA.
As I passed the previous created the graph and I started from zero to start making that DFS algorithm.
I want from you guys to write these codes into your compiler, into your C compiler, and that's the
code.
And tell me the results in the comments below.
So I'm getting your answers.
Now, let's now, let's implement that.